<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-10-24T22:44:07-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Bike Affair</title><subtitle>The bike side</subtitle><author><name>Shane Buscher</name></author><entry><title type="html">Training Commences</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/training/training-commences/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Training Commences" /><published>2018-10-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-10-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/training/training-commences</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/training/training-commences/">&lt;p&gt;Training actually commenced 3 weeks ago, a few days after official notification that I was in for the first annual &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iowawindandrock.com&quot;&gt;Iowa Wind and Rock&lt;/a&gt;. There’s no magic formula on training for a 340 mile gravel race. My goal was just to get started with some base training as my riding and racing severely declined since mid-summer, leaving me in a pretty deep fitness hole. I turned to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trainerroad.com&quot;&gt;Trainer Road &lt;/a&gt;, which I used last winter, for a plan to get me going in short fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trainer Road breaks up training into Base, Build and Specialty Phases:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/structured-training.PNG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/structured-training.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within each phase you choose an appropriate target and volume. Here’s my initial approach:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Phase&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Target&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Volume&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Length&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Base&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Sweet Spot Base&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Mid Volume I &amp;amp; II&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;12 weeks&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Build&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Sustained Power&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Mid Volume&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8 weeks&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Specialty&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Century&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Mid Volume&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8 weeks&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sweet Spot Base is a Trainer Road staple for all cycling disciplines and provides foundational aerobic and strength endurance. There are different options for the Build Phase to choose depending on what you want to focus on. I chose Sustained Power as there will be plenty of sustainment needed for such a long race. It’s not like I’m looking for short power, I need to work on the diesel engine. After I hopefully boost my FTP in this phase, Specialty is next. I was deciding between mountain bike Cross Country Marathon and the road Century plan. Since I’m training for a gravel &lt;em&gt;road&lt;/em&gt; race it makes more sense to do Century, which also will likely include longer training rides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mid Volume weeks roughly amount to six hours of commitment. You might be wondering why I am not choosing the High Volume option, which averages 9 hours/week. I’m training to potentially race for 34 hours straight right? Well, even the most seasoned cyclists have a tough time with Trainer Road High Volume plans. I’m hardly seasoned at my current level of fitness. I don’t want to crash and burn by taking on so much training load so soon. It’s a journey. What I’m looking to do instead is adding an extra workout per week if I feel up to it. I’ll also be sprinkling in some epic training rides during the Build and Specialty phases as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding up the lengths of each base, build and specialty phases gives a grand total of 28 weeks. Damn, that’s over a half a year! Having a plan makes it easy to determine when training needs to start. I just had to subtract 28 weeks from April 20, 2019. After using a date calculator courtesy of Google, I needed to start October 8th. However, training doesn’t always go as planned. Vacations, sickness, and general life events can all delay training, so I added two more weeks of buffer time to make sure I can finish the entire plan. Training officially commenced September 24.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m putting a nail in this post. I wanted to go over some weekly workouts, review the new Trainer Road calendar and tell you about the pain cave. However, I want to keep these posts relatively short and more frequent. Look for these topics plus a possible race report from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/BT-Epic-163175240368241/&quot;&gt;BT Epic&lt;/a&gt; that I’m heading to this weekend. Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Shane Buscher</name></author><category term="iowa-wind-and-rock" /><summary type="html">Training actually commenced 3 weeks ago, a few days after official notification that I was in for the first annual Iowa Wind and Rock. There’s no magic formula on training for a 340 mile gravel race. My goal was just to get started with some base training as my riding and racing severely declined since mid-summer, leaving me in a pretty deep fitness hole. I turned to Trainer Road , which I used last winter, for a plan to get me going in short fashion.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I Won the Lottery</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/gravel/i-won-the-lottery/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I Won the Lottery" /><published>2018-10-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-10-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/gravel/i-won-the-lottery</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/gravel/i-won-the-lottery/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/windandrockbanner.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Iowa Wind and Rock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did have to share the lottery &lt;em&gt;win&lt;/em&gt; with 119 others. You see, there were even more deranged individuals besides myself who entered the chance to race 340 miles of rural Iowa gravel roads. In April when the weather is entirely unpredictable. Within 34 hours. Not knowing the route ahead of time. Self navigated. With a handful of checkpoints and probably fewer convenience stores for resupply. Oh, and no outside support allowed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did I say there were 120 spots available and there was more demand, forcing a lottery to get into this free event? A few years back I entered the lottery to get into &lt;a href=&quot;http://transiowa.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Trans Iowa&lt;/a&gt;, but &lt;em&gt;lost&lt;/em&gt;. Trans Iowa was the predecessor to this race, called &lt;a href=&quot;https://iowawindandrock.com/&quot;&gt;Iowa Wind and Rock&lt;/a&gt;. Might be more like mud and pebbles. Nonetheless, I’m in! This could simultaneously be the dumbest and best thing I’ve ever done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Might as well fire up a blog to document the journey to April 20th, 2019. I suppose I’ll do a race report too afterwards, if I have enough strength left to tap the keyboard. The blog is really for me, not you (no offense). Don’t worry, you’ll have plenty of opportunities to laugh at me. Until next time…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Shane Buscher</name></author><category term="iowa-wind-and-rock" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>