<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-10-29T21:47:30-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Bike Affair</title><subtitle>The bike side</subtitle><author><name>Shane Buscher</name></author><entry><title type="html">2018 BT Epic</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mtb/bt-epic-race-report/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2018 BT Epic" /><published>2018-10-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-10-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mtb/bt-epic-race-report</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mtb/bt-epic-race-report/">&lt;p&gt;I was first introduced to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/BT-Epic-163175240368241/&quot;&gt;BT Epic&lt;/a&gt; in 2016 and missed it the following year. The &lt;em&gt;BT&lt;/em&gt; refers to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mtbproject.com/trail/7026921/berryman-trail&quot;&gt;Berryman Trail&lt;/a&gt; located in Mark Twain National Forest. At one point in time it was designated as an IMBA Epic trail. The race course is roughly 50 miles of loose rock, 5000+ feet of climbing, fast and fun descents, a bit of gravel roads and double track, and general flowy singletrack goodness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2018-elevation.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2018-elevation.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;BT Epic elevation profile&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was excited to take my first trip in the MTBLIMO to Steelville, MO where the race is held. The plan was to drive halfway to Independence, MO Thursday evening and get to the venue around noonish Friday. So after work Thursday I headed to R&amp;amp;R’s abode, we packed up the sprinter and headed south. There was lots of room to stretch out with only Alex and I in the back. Ryan played an Arcade Fire tribute on the way for me, somehow remembering I went to a show several years ago. We made it to our destination that night with quite the buggy windshield, got some grub and checked into the hotel. It was lights out a bit after ten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2018-limo.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2018-limo.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;MTBLIMO internals&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got up decently early on Friday morning after a noisy night at the hotel. We headed across the street to Denny’s for some coffee and breakfast before heading out. Coincidentally Alex had been to this Denny’s before a while back after playing a gig. I partook in a Grand Slam breakfast to begin fueling up for race day. After filling up we made our way to Steelville and got checked in at Bass River Resort, where the race is actually held. Steelville is just the closest town. R&amp;amp;R hooked up with two A-frame cabins there. Mike was meeting us at Bass River that afternoon and EOB and AOB would be arriving later in the evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2018-cabins.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2018-cabins.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Accomodations&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike arrived just a bit after we did and a decision of when to pre-ride the course had to be made. It was a dreary, rainy day unlike the picture above taken Saturday. Thinking the rain would not let up anytime soon, we decided to hit it. This was Alex’s first race here so we rode up the 4 mile gravel ascent from the start and headed into the singletrack. The roots and rocks were slippery as hell on the initial steep descent and climb out from it. However, after that the flow kicked in and all was good. We rode a soggy 1.5 hours, came back to the cabin to change and warm up, then headed to registration. I picked up a hat/coffee cup/koozie combo at registration while Alex made a new friend!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2018-bulldog.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2018-bulldog.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That evening Roxy made some tasty carnitas and rice with all the fixings of guac, salsa, sour cream and cheese. The perfect meal the night before a race. We stuffed our gullets then did our remaining race prep duties. I noticed my front tire went flat that evening and narrowed the issue down to the valve core. Ryan came to my rescue with a spare, as I did not have any. The bad core didn’t want to unscrew and Mike ended up jumping in to help. Since I am mechanically declined I need all the help I can get. Thanks to Ryan and Mike the issue was resolved and my front tire was good to go. We all planned to get up pretty darn early- 5:30am, so it was lights out around 10. zzzzzz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alex and I had beds up in the loft and his ahooga horn alarm fired off next to me at 5:30am. Race day! With the race starting at 8:30am, we all wanted to down our breakfast at least 2 hours before. Normally I eat some oatmeal and fruit. I had the latter covered with some dried mangos, but in lieu of oatmeal I chowed on peanut butter granola. After eating it was just killing time, kitting up and sipping a low carb Monster. Our cabin was a five minute ride to the start line, so Alex and I headed over around 8am. While the sun pushed out the rainy weather from the previous day, the temp was a shade under 45 and with a high in the low 60s- what I would call perfect riding weather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the start I found the truck to throw my drop bag containing 2 bottles mixed with Tailwind and Scratch, plus some salted watermelon gels. The bags get sent off to aid station 2 of 4. I stuck another bottle in my only cage and another in my jersey. Besides that I carried the typical extra tube, tire lever, C02, multitool and more gels. At 8:30am the gun fired and wave 1 took off, then wave 2 peeps like me pulled up to the start. We would go 5 minutes after wave 1. I lined up at the front and the photographer caught a great pic with, from left to right, Ryan, Alex, me and EOB. I guess EOB and I must have been looking at our computers…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2018-start-line.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2018-start-line.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Wave 2 start line courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/BGstudiosphotography/?__tn__=kC-R&amp;amp;eid=ARDdYGvxydhvEvyDh7_ejvm8GxIuU-rcAPMALVnOsW2XIuo43jTmdHa909VoCF5Jou33qvMLQQB4FU5d&amp;amp;hc_ref=ARToYE9jj6hqwcF8SMKSHQnqQTdBftv_MGa1ZizqeZ0fR0DE2-oi4bm_BlORbdwVHPY&amp;amp;__xts__[0]=68.ARBPUahtosOUgGnIMVvVBggjzKXDCirMXQIGny3bluOeSqOqAdtvN5ScOb55Kd8f2754OQvPBRZNDeHRaJDYAoAP2A6EZ9ju_f1f1-Yv3CBBIqJPlAU-9kXp_MpNMcYJjrGJvdEdAUZlU9bPgxNeXfrrJGfsPGUx2gj8dOlRAFaX08r7sxUlw1UPzGzANbd1RSQlAD7zmLGxyJVlQ30japd6ENY&quot;&gt;BGstudios Photography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before going into race details, let’s talk goals. I wasn’t out to necessarily &lt;em&gt;race&lt;/em&gt;. As I’ve mentioned in past posts I signed up for the 340 mile Iowa Wind and Rock (IWAR) gravel race in April 2019. I didn’t want to blow up my training schedule that I started a few weeks earlier by racing hard at BT Epic. The goal was to match my pace to a few of the sweet spot base workouts on my training schedule for the current training week. This meant staying below threshold as much as possible for the entire race. This took a lot of self-induced pressure off myself and gave me a chance to just ride a fun course on a great Fall day while getting my training load in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting back to the start line, the race director said a few words and Ryan was cracking jokes. Soon the gun went off I got clipped in quickly and made my way towards the early left hand turn. The initial pace wasn’t too hard. There was 4.5 miles of uphill gravel to sort things out before the singletrack plus it was wave 2 after all. After rounding the corner the photographer caught Ryan in the lead with myself and Alex behind him. Do I look great in pink or what?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2018-start.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2018-start.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Wave 2 first corner courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/BGstudiosphotography/?__tn__=kC-R&amp;amp;eid=ARDdYGvxydhvEvyDh7_ejvm8GxIuU-rcAPMALVnOsW2XIuo43jTmdHa909VoCF5Jou33qvMLQQB4FU5d&amp;amp;hc_ref=ARToYE9jj6hqwcF8SMKSHQnqQTdBftv_MGa1ZizqeZ0fR0DE2-oi4bm_BlORbdwVHPY&amp;amp;__xts__[0]=68.ARBPUahtosOUgGnIMVvVBggjzKXDCirMXQIGny3bluOeSqOqAdtvN5ScOb55Kd8f2754OQvPBRZNDeHRaJDYAoAP2A6EZ9ju_f1f1-Yv3CBBIqJPlAU-9kXp_MpNMcYJjrGJvdEdAUZlU9bPgxNeXfrrJGfsPGUx2gj8dOlRAFaX08r7sxUlw1UPzGzANbd1RSQlAD7zmLGxyJVlQ30japd6ENY&quot;&gt;BGstudios Photography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I lined up front I knew there would be plenty of riders passing me since I needed to just ride steady. So I took it easy up the gravel and watched Alex and Ryan move ahead up the road. Alex was crushing it at the front, literally, and moved further up from Ryan. In my head I thought I’d never see them again until the finish, but as I approached the singetrack entrance I encountered chaos and confusion. I looked up the hill saw a slew of riders who must have missed the entrance and now were backtracking. Ryan, who had to be ahead of me by several minutes, was one of them. Turns out there was supposed to be a white truck at the entrance. There was not, and from the rider banter it sounded like the majority of wave 1 missed the turn along with a good chunk of wave 2. This was a (BT) Epic Fail. I was now ahead of wave 1 even though they started 5 minutes ahead. I let that settle in a bit on the first descent, eventually coming to the realization that I’m going to get passed, like a lot. It was just a matter of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was roughly 5 more miles to aid staion 1 so I just got in an easy groove and kept my heart rate in check (no powah meter on the mtb). I got passed some but mainly peeps from wave 2. There was no need to stop at Aid 1 as my two bottles would last until the next station. However, the traffic started getting heavier between aid stations 1 &amp;amp; 2. I was starting to see the front of wave 1 riders, and they were generally riding pissed. While most did call out to go around, a few didn’t provide the courtesy. Opportunities to pass were sometimes hard to come by With so much of the trail being bench cut. There was no room. Seemed like it took forever for me to get to the second aid station, partly due to the traffic. When I did roll in I saw Alex refueling. He said he went well over a mile past the singletrack entrance. While feeling bad for him, I was silently glad I didn’t go out hard because I’d be in the same situation (sorry Alex). It took me a while to find my bag at aid 2 as there were hundreds of them, all identical except for bib number markings. No worries for me that day though. With some sleuthing I found my bag and swapped my bottles out, ate a gel and chugged a separate bottle of water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After leaving aid 2 there’s a fun downhill that takes your mind off any fatigue you’ve accumulated. However, there’s also a 300 foot climb along a 1 mile section. I think that’s where Roxy passed me in a train of wave 1 riders. She happened to be the caboose. Not too long after I saw AOB coming up from behind in her stars and stripes jersey. She also started in wave 1 and was on a mission. I was in a group and yelled out ‘a marathon national champ is coming around us!’. AOB wasted no time and before I knew it, she was gone. At the end of the race I found out she went 5 miles past the singletrack entrance. After the major climbing there’s another long, rewarding descent before you have to climb back up double-track to the unmanned aid station 3. I ended up stopping to get some water and helped out two others with filling their hydration packs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theres’ several miles of gradual uphill gravel after leaving aid 3. It was getting monotonous and for the first time that day I wasn’t having any fun. But some of the fastest, flowiest fun of the course starts where the gravel ends. This immediately pumped me back up and was now flying high. By now everyone around me was spread out and I could ride free. That is, until the three sisters show up. Three steep, technical climbs in a row that will test your limits. After that pain you end up riding the road back towards the start line where the last aid station is. I was hydrated well and I still had a full bottle, so I rode on by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point there’s approximately 9 miles left, but it’s tough going. Definitely not like the Dakota Five-O where it’s all downhill pleasure to the finish. You first climb up a paved road 300 feet, then steady climb on a gravel road for several miles but seems like an eternity. You get some downhill singletrack action after to recover, but IMHO, you are faced with the most agonizing climb of the course. It’s about 250 feet in 0.75 miles, and my legs were on fire. Even though I kept it steady all day I was definitely still fatigued. After pedaling to the top I knew the remaining couple of miles were mostly downhill and the end was near. I went through the old finish area and continued to the new finish line at the event center. Along the final stretch there was a rider walking his bike in, a flat victim. Who knows how far he had to walk, but he wasn’t alone. The course was riddled with riders changing flats the entire day. Mike ended up having three but was prepared to fix a dozen. Anyhoo, I crossed the finish line in 6:09 and some change, at least that’s what my Bolt said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like any 50 miler, it’s always a sweet feeling when you finish. I was OK with my time, although in the back of my head I wanted 6 hours or less. No big whoop though. I found most of the crew inside the event center and we chowed down on some BBQ. Then we headed back to the cabin to clean up and work on all the bourbon we brought :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2018-whiskey.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2018-whiskey.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Post race refreshments&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all, and our bourbon, piled in the MTBLIMO in the early evening to hit awards back at the event center. As you can see for yourself, things got weird. I was seeing double AOBs and half of a EOB head. We were all having a great time but the event center was a bit more stuffy than the giant chuckwagon tent of past years. When the race director got on the mic he was very apologetic about the missing truck and vowed that it would not happen again. He is dedicated to make the BT Epic the best race out there, and he is forgiven in my book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2018-awards.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2018-awards.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congrats to AOB for taking 4th place in Women U35 (11th overall) and Roxy for taking 3rd place in Women 35+ (4th overall). These ladies are warriors! Alex took home a 12 pack of Corona for getting the wave 2 hole shot. Even EOB was a winner after getting his name called in the raffle. He ended up getting a sweet Kuat bike rack for AOB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;third&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2018-4th.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2018-4th.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2018-top-10.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2018-top-10.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2018-holeshot.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2018-holeshot.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for my full stats on the day, here they are in addition to 2016. This is more for my comparison, but you can see I was roughly 35 minutes slower. Between taking it easy and the amount of time lost with passing, that seems about right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;align-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2018-summary.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2018-summary.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;2018 summary&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;align-center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2016-summary.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2016-summary.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;2016 summary&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did a good job overall of sticking below threshold. While I only have heart rate data to compare, you can see that I spent the vast majority of my time this year in tempo versus more of a tempo/threshold split in 2016:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2018-hr.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2018-hr.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;2018 heart rate analysis&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2016-hr.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bt-epic-2016-hr.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;2016 heart rate analysis&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last thing I want to do is thank R&amp;amp;R for letting me tag along. They are incredibly generous and equally passionate about mountain biking. They took care of all the travel logistics and make going to out of town races so easy. Thanks again R&amp;amp;R!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Shane Buscher</name></author><category term="race" /><category term="btepic" /><summary type="html">I was first introduced to the BT Epic in 2016 and missed it the following year. The BT refers to the Berryman Trail located in Mark Twain National Forest. At one point in time it was designated as an IMBA Epic trail. The race course is roughly 50 miles of loose rock, 5000+ feet of climbing, fast and fun descents, a bit of gravel roads and double track, and general flowy singletrack goodness.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Training Commences</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/training/training-commences/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Training Commences" /><published>2018-10-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-10-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/training/training-commences</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/training/training-commences/">&lt;p&gt;Training actually commenced 3 weeks ago, a few days after official notification that I was in for the first annual &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iowawindandrock.com&quot;&gt;Iowa Wind and Rock&lt;/a&gt;. There’s no magic formula on training for a 340 mile gravel race. My goal was just to get started with some base training as my riding and racing severely declined since mid-summer, leaving me in a pretty deep fitness hole. I turned to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trainerroad.com&quot;&gt;Trainer Road &lt;/a&gt;, which I used last winter, for a plan to get me going in short fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trainer Road breaks up training into Base, Build and Specialty Phases:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/structured-training.PNG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/structured-training.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within each phase you choose an appropriate target and volume. Here’s my initial approach:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Phase&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Target&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Volume&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Length&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Base&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Sweet Spot Base&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Mid Volume I &amp;amp; II&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;12 weeks&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Build&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Sustained Power&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Mid Volume&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8 weeks&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Specialty&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Century&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Mid Volume&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8 weeks&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sweet Spot Base is a Trainer Road staple for all cycling disciplines and provides foundational aerobic and strength endurance. There are different options for the Build Phase to choose depending on what you want to focus on. I chose Sustained Power as there will be plenty of sustainment needed for such a long race. It’s not like I’m looking for short power, I need to work on the diesel engine. After I hopefully boost my FTP in this phase, Specialty is next. I was deciding between mountain bike Cross Country Marathon and the road Century plan. Since I’m training for a gravel &lt;em&gt;road&lt;/em&gt; race it makes more sense to do Century, which also will likely include longer training rides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mid Volume weeks roughly amount to six hours of commitment. You might be wondering why I am not choosing the High Volume option, which averages 9 hours/week. I’m training to potentially race for 34 hours straight right? Well, even the most seasoned cyclists have a tough time with Trainer Road High Volume plans. I’m hardly seasoned at my current level of fitness. I don’t want to crash and burn by taking on so much training load so soon. It’s a journey. What I’m looking to do instead is adding an extra workout per week if I feel up to it. I’ll also be sprinkling in some epic training rides during the Build and Specialty phases as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding up the lengths of each base, build and specialty phases gives a grand total of 28 weeks. Damn, that’s over a half a year! Having a plan makes it easy to determine when training needs to start. I just had to subtract 28 weeks from April 20, 2019. After using a date calculator courtesy of Google, I needed to start October 8th. However, training doesn’t always go as planned. Vacations, sickness, and general life events can all delay training, so I added two more weeks of buffer time to make sure I can finish the entire plan. Training officially commenced September 24.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m putting a nail in this post. I wanted to go over some weekly workouts, review the new Trainer Road calendar and tell you about the pain cave. However, I want to keep these posts relatively short and more frequent. Look for these topics plus a possible race report from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/BT-Epic-163175240368241/&quot;&gt;BT Epic&lt;/a&gt; that I’m heading to this weekend. Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Shane Buscher</name></author><category term="iowa-wind-and-rock" /><summary type="html">Training actually commenced 3 weeks ago, a few days after official notification that I was in for the first annual Iowa Wind and Rock. There’s no magic formula on training for a 340 mile gravel race. My goal was just to get started with some base training as my riding and racing severely declined since mid-summer, leaving me in a pretty deep fitness hole. I turned to Trainer Road , which I used last winter, for a plan to get me going in short fashion.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I Won the Lottery</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/gravel/i-won-the-lottery/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I Won the Lottery" /><published>2018-10-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-10-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/gravel/i-won-the-lottery</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/gravel/i-won-the-lottery/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/windandrockbanner.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Iowa Wind and Rock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did have to share the lottery &lt;em&gt;win&lt;/em&gt; with 119 others. You see, there were even more deranged individuals besides myself who entered the chance to race 340 miles of rural Iowa gravel roads. In April when the weather is entirely unpredictable. Within 34 hours. Not knowing the route ahead of time. Self navigated. With a handful of checkpoints and probably fewer convenience stores for resupply. Oh, and no outside support allowed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did I say there were 120 spots available and there was more demand, forcing a lottery to get into this free event? A few years back I entered the lottery to get into &lt;a href=&quot;http://transiowa.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Trans Iowa&lt;/a&gt;, but &lt;em&gt;lost&lt;/em&gt;. Trans Iowa was the predecessor to this race, called &lt;a href=&quot;https://iowawindandrock.com/&quot;&gt;Iowa Wind and Rock&lt;/a&gt;. Might be more like mud and pebbles. Nonetheless, I’m in! This could simultaneously be the dumbest and best thing I’ve ever done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Might as well fire up a blog to document the journey to April 20th, 2019. I suppose I’ll do a race report too afterwards, if I have enough strength left to tap the keyboard. The blog is really for me, not you (no offense). Don’t worry, you’ll have plenty of opportunities to laugh at me. Until next time…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Shane Buscher</name></author><category term="iowa-wind-and-rock" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>